MING WEN

Email: mwenaa@cse.ust.hk

Phone: 852-59332175, +86-13048835479 Homepage: www.cse.ust.hk/~mwenaa

SHORT BIO

I have completed my PhD thesis defense from the department of Computer Science and Engineering of the Hong Kong University of Science and Technology. It's my honour to be supervised by Prof. Shing-Chi CHEUNG. My research interests mainly focus on program analysis, mining software changes, fault localization and program repair. I have visited University of California, Davis for half a year from Jul 2017 to Jan 2018 under the supervision of Prof. Zhendong Su. Before joining HKUST, I received my Bachelor Degree in June 2014 from Zhejiang University, Hangzhou, China.

EDUCATION

The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology

Sep, 2014 - Mar, 2019

Ph.D., Computer Science, Supervised by Prof. Shing-Chi CHEUNG

scc@cse.ust.hk

• Fields: Program Analysis, Mining Software Changes, Fault Localization and Program Repair

Zhejiang University

Sep, 2010 - Jun, 2014

B.A., Computer Science and Technology (Major)

B.A., Industrial Design (Dual Major)

Graduated as Outstanding Students in Both the University and Zhejiang Province

EXPERIENCES

Visitor Scholar at University of California, Davis, California, USA Supervised by Prof. Zhendong SU

Research Intern at Microsoft Research Asia, Beijing, China

Supervised by Shi HAN

Research Intern at HKUST, Hong Kong

Supervised by Shing-Chi CHEUNG

Jul. 2017 - Jan. 2018 zhendong.su@inf.ethz.ch

Mar. 2014 - Jun. 2014 shihan@microsoft.com

Sep. 2013 - Mar. 2014

Publications

- EASE'19: Shangwen Wang, Ming Wen, Xiaoguang Mao, Deheng Yang. Attention Please: Consider Mockito when valuating Newly Proposed Automated Program Repair Techniques. In the Conference of Evaluation and Assessment in Software Engineering (EASE), To Appear, 2019
- ICSE'19: Ming Wen, Yepang Liu, Rongxin Wu, Xuan Xie, Shing-Chi Cheung and Zhendong Su. Exposing Library API Misuses via Mutation Analysis. In Proceedings of the 41th International Conference on Software Engineering, 2019. (Acceptance ratio 20.9%=109/529). (CCF-A)
- ICSE'19: Ying Wang, Ming Wen, Zhenwei Liu, Shin Hwei Tan, Zhiliang Zhu, Hai Yu and Shing-Chi Cheung. Can I Have a Stack Trace to Examine the Dependency Conflict Issue? In Proceedings of the 41th International Conference on Software Engineering, 2019. (Acceptance ratio 20.9%=109/529). (CCF-A)
- TSE'18: Ming Wen, Rongxin Wu and Shing-Chi Cheung. How Well Do Change Sequences Predict Defects? Sequence Learning from Software Changes. In Transactions of Software Engineering, 2018. (CCF-A)
- ESEC/FSE'18: Ying Wang, Ming Wen, Zhenwei Liu, Rongxin Wu, Rui Wang, Bo Yang, Hai Yu, Zhiliang Zhu and Shing-Chi Cheung. Do the Dependency Conflicts in My Project Matter?

In The ACM Joint European Software Engineering Conference and Symposium on the Foundations of Software Engineering. Technical Research Paper, Lake Buena Vista, Florida, 4 Nov - 9 Nov, 2018. (Acceptance ratio 21.1%=61/289). (CCF-A)

- ICSE'18: Ming Wen, Junjie Chen, Rongxin Wu, Dan Hao and Shing-Chi Cheung. Context-Aware Patch Generation for Better Automated Program Repair. In Proceedings of the 40th International Conference on Software Engineering. Technical Research Paper, Gothenburg, Sweden, 27 May 3 June, 2018. (Acceptance ratio 20.9%=105/502). (CCF-A)
- EmSE'17: Rongxin Wu, Ming Wen, Shing-Chi Cheung and Hongyu Zhang. ChangeLocator: Locate Crash-Inducing Changes Based on Crash Reports. In Empirical Software Engineering. 2017. (CCF-B)
- ASE'16: Ming Wen, Rongxin Wu and Shing-Chi Cheung. Locus: Locating Bugs from Software Changes. In Proceedings of the 31st IEEE/ACM International Conference on Automated Software Engineering. Technical Research Paper, Singapore, 3 Sep 7 Sep, 2016. (Acceptance ratio 19.1%=57/298). (CCF-A)
- SANER'14: Xin Xia, David Lo, Ming Wen, Emad Shihab and Bo Zhou. An Empirical Study of Bug Report Field Reassignment. Joint Meeting of the 18th European Conference on Software Maintenance and Reengineering and the 21st Working Conference on Reverse Engineering. 2014

AWARDS AND HONORS

Postgraduate Scholarship, the Hong Kong University of Science and Technology S	Sep. 2014 - Now
Top Research Post-Graduate Award, School of Engineering, HKUST	Jul. 2018
Research Travel Grant for ICSE'2018, HKUST	May. 2018
Best TA Award, the Hong Kong University of Science and Technology	2017-2018
Overseas Research Award, School of Engineering, HKUST	2016-2017
Research Travel Grant for ASE'2016, HKUST	Sep. 2016
School of Engineering (SENG) PhD Fellowship Award, SENG, HKUST	2014-2015
Excellent Certificate of Stars of Tomorrow Internship Program, MSRA	Jun. 2014
Outstanding Graduates of Zhejiang University, Zhejiang University National Scholarship, Ministry of Education of People's Republic of China	Jun. 2014 Oct. 2013
First-Class Scholarship for Outstanding Students, Zhejiang University Excellent Student Awards, Zhejiang University Outstanding Student Leader Awards, Zhejiang University	Dec. 2012 Dec. 2012 Dec. 2012

SERVICE

Reviewer of Empirical Software Engineering	2018
Reviewer of ACM Transaction of Software Engineering and Methodology	2018
Reviewer of IEEE Transaction on Reliability	2018
External Reviewer of International Conference on Software Engineering	2017
Student Volunteer of FSE, Hong Kong	2014

TEACHING

Teaching Assistant of COMP3021, Java Programming, HKUST	Fall. 2016
Teaching Assistant of COMP1022Q, Introduction to Computing with Excel VBA	Spring. 2016
Teaching Assistant of COMP2011, Introduction to Object-Oriented Programming	Fall. 2015
Teaching Assistant of COMP3021, Java Programming, HKUST	Spring. 2015
LANGUAGE	

 ${\bf Mandarin~Chinese~(Native),~English~(Fluent)}$